Alexandru Visan



alexandruvisan1908@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/visan-alexandru



+40 721 642 772



https://alexvisan.netlify.app/

Summary

Hi, I'm a Front End Developer and I love working on web projects and creating beautiful user interfaces. I strive to create an intuitive and enjoyable experience for users, while also keeping the code clean and organized.

I've been working in the software industry for over 5 years starting as a Quality Assurance, gaining experience while learning the basics of user experience as an Email Marketer, and finally finding my stride as a Software Engineer.

While over these years I have gained a lot of experience in both testing code and front-end, my passion lies in the front-end using new technologies and frameworks to create interactive websites.

When I'm not coding, I like to spend time with my family and friends.

Experience



Software Engineer

Tremend Software Consulting

Jun 2022 - Present (1 year 2 months)

Worked on two new projects (Hiring processes app and Voting system app) in the first 3 months using react, redux toolkit, react form hook, styled-components and MUI for the company to improve workflow for HR and hiring managers and to make easier for people to vote.

Currently I'm in a project where the client is Carrefour and we are building an application for them to make it easier to create promotional pages. The tech stack we are using revolves around Next.js.

888 Frontend Developer

888Sparkware

Nov 2018 - Jun 2022 (3 years 8 months)

Building the website from concept all the way to completion.

Cooperating with web designers to match visual design intent and execute all visual design stages, everything from the home page to site layout, templates and performing ongoing QA.

Responsible for maintaining, expanding, and scaling websites.

Collaborating with internal teams to identify system requirements.

Develop existing tools and new once for any of the BU requirements.

888 Email Marketing

888Sparkware

Oct 2017 - Nov 2018 (1 year 2 months)

Code marketing campaign communications in HTML and CSS from scratch.

Creation/ implementation/testing of emails, client communications, pushes, SMS.

Run A/B tests to help optimize open rates, CTR and conversion rate.

QA Engineer

Web Future Studio & Solutions

Nov 2016 - Oct 2017 (1 year)

Actively participated in daily meetings with project managers and developers in order to review requirements, create test cases and providing support to developers as needed. Reporting any detected bugs into the issue tracking database(Jira) and evaluating changes requests and estimating the required effort needed for compliance. Maintained open communication with internal teams of back-end developers and designers to actively send daily reports with testing results.

Senior QA Tester

Gameloft

Dec 2014 - Oct 2016 (1 year 11 months)

My main responsibilities included:

- -following IOS checklist guide rules with precision (a set of rules special created for all IOS games)
- -participating in mass testing. (mass-testing events are organized by the QA department in order to test the server response, which needs a high number of participants at the same time. In most cases, the main interest is on the performance of the server and the client in extreme situations.)
- -testing the new Companion App of BIA3 on Apple Watch.
- -helping the new colleagues to understand the given task.
- -participating in stress and compatibility tests.
- -different social networks tests scenarios (inviting friends, sending gifts, observing the leaderboards
- -setting and testing the implementation of the GL Ads :
- the ad is displayed correctly, -the corresponding tracking and click impressions for each Ad type is registered on the Hits page. - the redirect link (external, in-game or cross-promo) inside the Ad works checking that the GL Ads are available in the AUT in the locations set.
- -checking that the GL Ads refresh between different sections, regardless of the direction the user navigates.

Education



Titu Maiorescu University

Licenta in Informatica, Matematică și informatică 2013 - 2016

Skills

```
TypeScript • styled-components • Material-UI • Redux Toolkit • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) •
JavaScript • CSS3 • React.js • jQuery • HTML
```